Um well, it's great to be with you guys.
Um we're uh obviously having just
selected Caleb, uh culmination of a very
lengthy and thorough process. Um just
want to, you know, I know we'll get a
chance, you know, as we work throughout
the weekend to really talk about just
the the process of the personnel
department and coaches led by, you know,
Rob really bringing this whole thing
together. Um really excited about adding
a player of Caleb's talent. um really
felt like we were able to identify a
player with the ceiling. Um you know,
what what we believe to be a top 10
caliber talent and and difference maker
potentially, you know, in a place where
we we really wanted to, you know, add
some size and youth to to that defensive
line. We feel really good about not only
Jaylen Redmond, but the rest of the
young guys in that room. um that now we
get to add, you know, a guy with a ton
of upside uh you know, between Flo and
Ryan Nielsen and their excitement uh of
the player and and and the way um you
know, we we use the process from the
combine formal uh to the 30 visit to
Ryan Nielsen spending some time with him
down um at at the University of Florida.
uh felt between that and the fact that
uh medically we feel uh strongly about
you know where Caleb's not only at right
now you know after really uh getting
that thing um you know totally fixed up
and and and having the type of medical
uh team here surgeon wise orthopedic
surgeon wise we have some of the best uh
in the world a lot of people around the
league come to you know some of our
folks uh specifically in regards to you
know foot and ankle stuff and uh you
know we spend a lot time, lengthy time,
just making sure we all felt uh really
good about it so that Caleb can um come
here with with the excitement that we
have for him and and quite honestly as
coaches can't wait to coach this player.
Um he loves football. um wants to be
coached hard and and and ultimately uh
believes that the Minnesota Vikings is a
great place for him to come and try to
maximize who he is as a player, not only
now, but where we think he can take uh
take this thing throughout his career
with the type of talent and ability that
he has.
>> Kevin, just what was the process
medically? I mean, how much, you know,
did you guys dive into to just his
history with kind of the feet? Yeah, we
uh you know we really you know we use
the we use the you know the extent of
the process that that uh we can we um
you know we we feel very strongly about
um not only Caleb but you know how we've
evaluated you know all the prospects in
the draft from a medical standpoint. Um
it is important that uh you know we
expect Caleb to have a a big-time impact
in 2026
um and beyond and and we wanted to feel
good about that and and what that looks
like from a standpoint of uh you know
him finishing up his recovery from where
he's at now. I know he has a lot of
confidence in where he's at. I know he
put out um the letter um kind of stating
that as well, but that was all
internally things we knew already. And
um I'm just, you know, it's it's a lot
of time and energy and focus to make
sure uh that when we were selecting a
player, you know, at 18 that that we
were selecting a player that has a
chance to really impact our
organization. Um, and at that position,
his size, his movement skills, his
violence, you know, the type of game
that we think he can play, snap in and
snap out is something we're really
excited about.
>> Can you speak to the idea of having one
of these guys in the interior that you
type of guy that you've gone up against
every week for the last
>> Yeah, I mean, Alec, you know, as well as
anybody, and a lot of you you folks in
here, we talk weekly, it seems like
throughout the season about where this
league has kind of gone to. the edge
rushers, the premier edge rushers are
clearly um you know a factor week in and
week out, but you know some of the
critical games uh even we've played
during during my time here. Um you know
you can go back to the 2022 playoff game
and you remember disruptors on the
inside uh affecting plays and and
affecting the outcome of that game and
and just where we're at, you know, from
a standpoint of of a league right now.
the disruption of the quarterback, you
know, on those weighty downs. We clearly
know how to do it with our scheme, uh,
Flo's, you know, and his staff have done
as as good a job as anybody, uh,
developing a scheme that is a problem.
Uh it's something that people really
have to think about, but we really went
into this process uh with a mindset of
can we uh it's it's really been uh you
know some time since we really you know
invested an an early pick in in the
interior of the defensive line and we
wanted to make sure that uh throughout
you know the process of evaluating the
the defensive group, the offensive group
as a whole um we found ourselves in a
position at pick 18 to to have the
opportunity to select a player with that
kind of upside and that kind of ability
and you know we would have loved to have
a full inventory of tape uh from the
2025 season. Um but the 2024 tape looked
really good and uh you know you know
between Flo and Ryan Nielsen and our
scouts and and personnel folks all
having a level of excitement about what
this player can be in a Minnesota
Vikings uniform. it, you know, we uh
we're excited about the potential of the
impact and you know, I always look at
things from a standpoint of when you
pull that card when when that name gets
announced. You know, I think about it,
you know, how I do in many ways, which
is when one of our opponents or maybe
one of the teams we're going to play
twice a year, you wonder what their, you
know, the first thought is when they
they uh they hear that name called and a
lot of the things that we've talked
about between Flow Scheme, some of the
players we have that we feel great about
already on our defense, and now adding a
player like this, I think there was
probably a thought or two about, you
know, what that could look like from
from their perspective. What kind of
assurances did you get from your medical
staff when you hear foot problems with a
individual that large that this won't be
something that's habitual throughout his
career? Yeah. And you know, I I think
you know, we really dove into the layers
of you you mentioned problems, you know,
with an S there. and and we really kind
of dove into, you know, you know,
exactly, you know, from a standpoint of
what that was from the first time, uh,
what it looked like, you know, in in in
the procedure that, you know, quote, you
know, quote unquote, fixed it and then
the the the time after that and got to a
place where we feel like with this last
procedure that he had, um, and and in
addition to that, just between, you
know, our doctors, and I don't want to
mention, you know, one or two of them,
you know, by name because they're, you
know, we have a great team. Um, but we
feel, you know, based upon the
percentages and the things that we how
we talk about these guys and the
likelihood of things and and the
positivity that came out of that
conversation, we feel really good about
it. And to be clear, but in terms of
that conversation, like your sense is
that he'll be ready and fully available
to you from the start of training camp
or or season or like there's no
>> Yeah, we're Yeah, we're working
backwards from a standpoint of obviously
the regular season, but more importantly
training camp. He's he's going to be a
rookie. You know, you guys know how we
handle the offseason program
specifically uh for those guys up front.
Um a lot of times it's uh that learning
and teaching phase he's still going to
be able to take part in. and he's still
going to be able to have uh the ability
to, you know, early on, you know, as as
a young player, be totally exposed, uh,
you know, above the neck to our scheme,
what we're going to be asking him of
him, and then as we work towards the end
of the offseason program on into the
summer, um, our hope is that, uh, you
know, we'll be able to prepare him for
the the regular season and have him for
that.
>> Evan, what kind of feedback did you get
from Pat Hill about Caleb down at the
senior pool? Yeah, that's one of the
great benefits of having u having your
coaches, whether it was Pat Hill, Ryan
Cordell, we had some others as well. Um,
but the the great thing is they have
access to, you know, Pat is in the
meeting room with these players. He's
installing things with these guys. he's,
you know, going through the one-on- ons
and going through some of the the drills
throughout the practices, the team
drills, uh, right there as their
position coach and really getting a feel
um, for a lot of the guys that we
evaluated very, you know, very much uh,
with great detail um, throughout the
process. But you find out some things
that quite honestly sometimes you you're
you're really trying to dive deep
through the school and through some of
your scouts on campus, coaches going on
campus and things to try to find out.
But the one thing Pat said uh was, you
know, it's clear this guy loves
football. It's clear this guy has the
ability to to be highly impactful. Um
and that was, you know, Caleb, you know,
obviously probably not at 100% quite
honestly um at that time and he was
still able to go, you know, able to
demonstrate so many things throughout
that week. Um and and Pat, you know, was
was really excited about the opportunity
of of adding to the conversation to
bring uh Caleb to Minnesota. Kevin, when
you say top 10 talent, um like how
unique is his twitchiness for how big he
is?
>> Well, I think like you know the one
thing that always checks the box is when
you have to when you're initially
watching the tape and you have to look
back on the height and weight because
it's hard to imagine sometimes with some
of the things he does. Um there's some
highlight worthy things that uh first
step hand usage violence. You know, he's
he's got the ability to push the pocket
from just a strength and mass
standpoint, but it's the movement
skills. Uh specifically in our defense
that is so valuable when you think about
uh the ability to to make the trip from
one gap to another or two gaps away and
create the advantage of getting him on
on edges, you know, on some individual
blocks. And um watching the way that has
worked for a guy like Jaylen Redmond in
his you know massive growth and
development here you you you see that a
player of Caleb's talent, his size, his
movement skills, you see a you see a
genuine real upside uh for a player that
uh I feel great about the guys between
Flo and Ryan Neielson, Pat Hill that are
going to be, you know, working with him
day in day out to help him reach a
ceiling. You know, drafting the player
is one thing, and I totally understand
the the questions uh about uh the
medical aspect of it. That's what we go
through and and got to a really good
place on it. But to me, the exciting
part is actively getting on the field,
getting these guys exposed to the rest
of our roster in the meeting rooms, uh
you know, all the thousand hours of
walkthroughs and individual drills and
then what the f what the final product
could look like for 2026. But the best
part of that is is what's beyond as
well. Um at a position where we see a
clear runway for the player to take off
and and have an immediate impact.
>> Can we with Ryan Nielson's um going down
there, was that just a private workout
or did you just spend time with him?
>> Spent time with him. Yeah, I spent time
with him and uh you know he I I I know
Rob will probably speak to this too, but
whether it was Keenan, whether it was uh
Ryan Nielsen, um Keith Carter, Curtis
Modkins, Mike Saravo, Gerald Alexander,
um you know, we had so many uh coaches,
you know, get off campus here and go to
their campuses for pro days. But it was
more than that. It was more about uh you
know, there were some individual
workouts throughout. There were some uh
there were some dinners, there were some
meetings, there was some classroom time.
We tried to be as thorough as we could
uh as a coaching staff really answering
the question of uh what is you know what
is this guy's football intelligence?
What is the upside? Uh what are the
ability for us to have an impact from a
learning standpoint of how how we're
going to teach these players. Um but
then at the same time, we're trying to
ask the question uh when it's all said
and done, does this player love
football? Does this player love going
out uh part of a pretty unique group of
guys in that locker room and joining
that and and uh you know feeling like
they're in a great position here to
match that love of football with the
type of development and and uh you know
type of wisdom that our coaches have
here and and you'd be hardressed to find
a better a better group than than Flo,
Ryan Neielson and Pat Hill. The sense
couple more questions here.
>> The sense online is that uh he's a
little bit raw or at least that's what
some of the online scouting
>> has indicated. Would that be your sense
as well? I mean, could he work into a
full helping of snack snap sometime for
week one, you know, provide health?
Yeah, I think yeah, I think the word raw
is is unique because uh not that I you
know I I don't know exactly the source
of of of what you what you found online,
but what I would say is uh the flashes
of high-end talent um are clearly there.
And uh I think that any young player
sometimes you know consistency can be a
thing specifically if they're working
through uh you know attempting to try to
work through you know doing those things
not at 100%. Uh so that's where the
question came back to first and foremost
medically uh can we get this player to a
place where we can have consistency from
a development standpoint, a practice
standpoint um and build up that snap
count. But we also feel really good
about the depth of the room. uh whether
you're talking about Tai Ingram, Levi,
Elijah Williams, and and we've already
talked about um Jaylen Redmond for sure.
And and we're our defense is so unique.
You know, we can morph from three down,
three down defense to four down defense.
We can have six on the line. We can, you
know, have every guy in a Vikings
uniform on the line of scrimmage if we
want to. Um, so it's a standpoint of
pulling from that world where we've got
inventory to try to then figure out
what's the best usage for Caleb to
obviously uh with those other 10 guys on
the field have the most impact, you
know, on the on the opponent we're
playing. Um, but also there's an
individual development standpoint where
um that's why you go get a guy like Ryan
Nielsen. That's why you go get uh Flo
and I identified him very very early on,
you know, and quite honestly uh you
know, this year wasn't the first time,
you know, we we attempted to bring Ryan
here uh because of that, you know, the
love of the development of that
position. uh the experience of working
with different types of players um along
that defense not only throughout his
time in New Orleans but then obviously
as his experience of being able to
understand the big picture as a
coordinator in two spots um you know and
that's that's where you feel like
whether you know some people might say
raw uh other people might say you know
if if he was those flashes uh for 13 14
15 plus games last year depending on how
they finished up uh if he was that a
little bit more consist assistant. Uh I
think we would have heard his name
called a heck of a lot earlier. And
that's where you uh you know, we don't
expect to be picking a lot earlier than
18th. Uh we haven't all that often. And
and and what what that means to me is
when you can identify that type of
talent and then go through a full
thorough process with a lot of people
that you lean on um from an expertise
standpoint medically, obviously Flo,
Ryan, and Pat. uh and then uh diving in
on, you know, what's what's inside that
player from a standpoint of love of
football, what the commitment to truly
reaching that ceiling is going to be. Um
and Caleb did a great job throughout
that process, as well as our medical
staff uh checking a lot all those boxes
for us.
>> Good.
>> Thanks, guys.
>> Thank you.